Pergola swings for Grammy and Grampy 2026.
All right, just bought 1,200 pounds of concrete,
20 bags, 60 lbs each,
and I'm gonna take it back
to Grammie and Grampie's.
And then I gotta dig the holes,
so I'm gonna get an auger,
and then I gotta put in the posts,
which I still haven't bought yet, so I
gotta come back here again to get posts.
And then after that,
I think we'll be set for tomorrow.
Uh, so this might have been me trying
to back up the car.
First time backing up, by the way.
But you know what?
We didn't hit anything.
The trailer's back here.
You know what?
I did pretty good, you know.
Also, check out the camera.
Sorry, Grammie and Grampie,
I'll move it back eventually.
Here we are again.
We've moved 5 of the 20 bags.
Uh, my back kind of hurts a little bit,
so I'm getting a break.
I'm back again.
Got all 20 bags out of the trailer
using this trusty wheelbarrow and me.
Got them all tarped up.
Might rain.
We don't know.
I guess I could look at the forecast,
but I don't know.
I think it's time to go get wood,
get all the posts and beams,
and then I gotta rent an auger.
This was us planning out the outline
of where the posts will go and just
getting a general idea of the shape.
All right, we've got all 4 holes dug.
That auger was a pain.
My back hurts.
This hole is a little
bigger cuz there was a rock.
Hole number 3.
Hole number 4.
Got to dig with the— whatever
you want to call it— hole digger.
Got to get all these a little deeper.
Bunch of dirt.
There's the concrete.
Okay,
then we got to get the posts in concrete,
but we first got to return the auger
because the rental's almost due.
Hey yo, thought I'd run a quick update.
Look, we got the posts in, right?
That's 1, 2, 3, 4.
Sawzall is out.
We're cutting off the tops
about a foot and 2 inches.
See that line?
I still got to cut these two.
Um, these will be sitting
from here on top to there on top.
Same here, and that, and that.
All right, very quick progress update.
All the bolts are into the boards.
The beams are attached to the posts.
This has got to get— they've all got to be
trimmed to be flush,
but progress is being made really good.
All right, another quick update.
It's been hot, like 3 hours,
been kind of slow.
We got this cut to be symmetrical to kind
of match the— that, you know,
that was the design that we're going for.
Also cut these.
This is going to be the back,
so I wanted a bit of a different design.
Um, 7 years of bad luck.
Um, yeah, I also got
all of those cut flush.
I think I might have already
talked about that, can't remember.
It's been 3 hours.
Um,
here's the, here's the one good thing we
actually got done, I, I think,
over here under the patio.
We've got this.
That's one.
The other one on the cart over there.
All right, another quick update.
We got this boy up and got
an extra 2x6 to structuralize that,
just give it more width.
Same here.
That's it so far, that extra width.
Um, yeah, we got both of these
up with the board up here.
I think I probably already said that,
but overall, let's give it a good look.
This is like from the back.
It's pretty big but looks pretty good.
Very late night update,
it's like 10:00 right now,
same spot where we were,
but might as well use the too short,
um, swinging hardware cuz we need
to get longer bolts or whatever anyways.
It's like, let's just use it.
And so hooked up a flag to him.
So now they can swing in the wind.
Pretty nice.
Um, just using this little light here
to shine on it.
Oh, it looks less pretty on this side.
Um, I kind of scooped up some
dirt and filled up the holes.
Now dirt's been moved
into the front yard as well.
Just some quick photos
right before sunset.
Looked very nice outside.
So I took some photos.
Hello, another progress update.
I think I already talked about the flag,
USA.
Um, I've gotten all of the lattices up.
They have not been cut yet.
I was just attaching the brackets,
so there's a bracket on each side now.
They're not attached,
they're just into the main beam.
There was only like 2 back
here that I've attached.
Cause I'm slacking, but I'm hungry,
so we're going to get food soon.
Um,
so yeah, I'll get all those brackets lined
up, screwed in,
and then we'll take all the boards off
again and cut the little,
uh, same angle as the— those over there.
Excuse me.
Same little cut right there, right?
And we'll do that for all of them.
But overall It's looking pretty solid.
Don't mind those ugly tags on the end
of the boards, but other than
that— hey, progress update!
We got both the swings attached.
We still need to go buy some chain to get
them a little closer to the ground,
because if you can't tell,
my feet are a little far.
Um, got all those bolted on.
We need to— see all these 2x2s?
We got a bunch over there.
Those need to be attached
to the top here, right?
You get that idea?
So I got to do that.
And we also got to go buy
little pieces of wood that'll go into the
little cup holder thing that flips down.
We're going to have the heart right here.
I have to cut that too.
I need two of them.
Final Progress update.
Check it out, we got everything done.
Got those top cross pieces,
we've got the side supports,
or whatever you want to call them.
All the swings are on.
Check out the hearts, that's awesome.
This one also is a heart.
Oh yeah, cup holders.
Um, Flag.
It's everything.
Take it Easy - The Eagles